Reginald Newsome

Experienced Mobile and Web Developer

Email

redhorizon.llc@gmail.com

Address

737 Delano Houston

Phone

+1 8329692784

Skype Address

l ive:.cid.449cc643fa06127d

Date of birth

Sep 18, 1978

Country

United State

Skills

Android, IOS, kotlin Swift, React-Native, Flutter Laravel, PHP, Python Express.js, React.js, Vue.js Git, Unit testing

Languages

English

Native

Spanish

Intermediate

SUMMARY

A high skilled mobile Developer with 9+ years of experience. Proven track record of developing, testing and maintaining complex applications. Deep understanding of programming languages and frameworks, as well as experience with mobile app architecture, and development methodologies. Strong problem-solving and designing skills.

EXPERIENCE

React-Native Developer

Civil Safety CompanyAug 2023 ~ Ongoing | Currumburra AUS
Developed an Online anytime application using React-Native, resulting in a
30% increase in sales

- Implemented various features using React-Native, including user authentication, offline workflow, UI dynamic creation, quiz engine and payment processing.
- Conducted automated and manual testing to ensure high-quality code and a seamless user experience.

Senior Full Stack Developer

Mayaal Company

Apr 2023~ Aug 2023 | Haramayn JORD

Developed a transport app(project name: Alnabali) using flutter and Laravel, resulting in a 30% increase in booking

- Implemented various features using flutter and Laravel, including admin panel, making Api, bus search functionality, user authentication, various notification, geolocation with google map and payment processing.
- Designed and optimized the database schema, reducing query times by 30%.
- Collaborated with a team of backend developers and product managers to prioritize and deliver new features on time.

Full Stack Developer

Century 21 Company

Nov 2022 ~ Apr 2023 | Agios CYPR

Built a Quiz application(project name: PlexyCube) using React- Native and Laravel, resulting in 3000+ active users

- Implemented various features using flutter and Laravel, scanning QR code, post creation, Restful Api endpoints and export and import excel file.

STRENGTHS

Problem Solver

Utilized problem solving skills to resolve complex technical issues, resulting in a 30% increase in overall efficiency

Team Player

Collaborate effectively with team members to develop, test and deploy new features, resulting in a 50% increase in customer satisfaction.

Detail Oriented

Demonstrated attention to detail in coding and testing, resulting in a 95% reducting in production bugs.

- Optimized page load times by implementing caching and reducing the number of SQL queries.
- Implemented to prevent questions that have been asked once from appearing again(There are more than 30,000 questions).
- Worked collaboratively with designer to deliver high-quality code on time and within budget

Senior Android Developer

ID SOLUTIONS Company Jul 2022 Oct 2022 | Valladolid Peru Built a Trip Jungle app using android, resulting in using by over 10,000+ users

- Implemented various features using Android(java), including Geolocation and Geofencing with google map, integration Alexa, AR using camera, and payment processing.
- Implemented to display a description of the location depending on the location using AR technology (the client got the idea from PokemonGo).
- Conducted automated and manual testing to ensure high-quality code and a seamless user experience.
- Collaborated with a team of backend developers and product managers to prioritize and deliver new features on time.

Senior React-Native Developer

Mayaal Company Apr 2021 ~ Jun 2022 | Haramayn, JORD Developed and maintained educational app for kids using react-native, resulting in 3000+ registered users.

- Implemented various features using React-Native, including search functionality, UI dynamic creation, user authentication and integration paypal.
- Considering the level of children, a function that uses drag as a basic function has also been implemented.
- Optimized the database schema, reducing query times by 25%.

Mid-level Android Developer

CodeBright Company Jan 2021 Apr 2021 Utica Square US Developed a WFG Finance application using android, resulting in a 20% increase in sales.

- Implemented application of various mathematical formulas, converting all functions in swift to android
- Conducted automated and manual testing to ensure high-quality code and a semless user experience

Swift Developer

Jobber Company

Apr 2020 ~ Jan 2021 | Toronto, CA

Build a Netory invoice application using swift, resulting in a 10% increase in sales.

- Implemented various features using swift, including user authentication, making invoice function, sending invoice to mail, and offline workflow.
- Collaborated with a team of developers and product managers to prioritize and deliver new features on time

Senior Swift Developer

Skill Bill Company

Oct 2019 Apr 2020 Milano ITA

Developed a MacOs application for SRT converting using swift, resulting in 60% reducing in working times.

- Implemented import the srt file and adjust the start and end times of the corresponding subtitles and to correct the overall time.
- Conducted automated and manual testing to ensure high-quality code and a seamless user experience

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Texas Southern University 3100 Cleburne St, Houston, TX 77004 1995 ~ 200